<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on Bernardo Reckziegel</title>
    <link>/categories/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on Bernardo Reckziegel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation Error Visualized</title>
      <link>/2019/02/27/estimation-error-visualized/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/27/estimation-error-visualized/</guid>
      <description>The objective of economic models is to dress common-sense into mathematical formalism. For some economic problems, however, data is too scare to achieve good statistical analysis. This scarcity of data leads to estimation-error1 (the econometricians enemy number one).
By estimation-error I mean: the researcher is never certain about the true data generating process (DGP) of the phenomenon at hand. As Allan Timmermann and Graham Elliott argue, economic models can be thought as a condense representation of reality, in which mispecifification flourish naturally2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio Analytics in the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>/2019/02/20/portfolio-analytics-in-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/20/portfolio-analytics-in-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Portfolio Analytics (PA) is a well known library for portfolio optimization in R. Written before the tidyverse gain pulse, the PA package is often used in the “Base R” context. The objective of this post is to show that it can also be use inside the tidyverse (with all the power that comes with it!).
The basic usage of portfolio Analytics can be found here. I’ll go straight to the tidy-world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dance of the Yield</title>
      <link>/2018/11/14/the-dance-of-yield/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/14/the-dance-of-yield/</guid>
      <description>Studying for the 2019 CFA Level III exam I came across a very interesting chapter on yield curve strategies. The content, among other things, explores the role of convexity and its importance in building custom views for expected returns.
The code below intents to visually show that the US yields indeed change in a non-linear fashion very often.
# load librarieslibrary(Quandl)library(tidyverse)library(gganimate)library(ggthemes)# download the yield from Quandlus_yields &amp;lt;- Quandl(&amp;quot;USTREASURY/YIELD&amp;quot;, collapse = &amp;quot;monthly&amp;quot;, order = &amp;quot;asc&amp;quot;)# express the maturity holdings in monthsmaturities &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;Date&amp;quot;, 1/12, 2/12, 3/12, 6/12, 1, 2, 3, 5, 7, 10, 20, 30)n &amp;lt;- nrow(us_yields)# create the plotp &amp;lt;- us_yields %&amp;gt;% as_tibble() %&amp;gt;% # change maturity names`colnames&amp;lt;-`(maturities) %&amp;gt;% # tidygather(&amp;quot;maturity&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;yields&amp;quot;, -Date) %&amp;gt;%mutate_if(is_character, as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Covariance Matrix</title>
      <link>/2018/09/08/a-covariance-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/08/a-covariance-matrix/</guid>
      <description>The function bellow is a transcription from the MATLAB code done by Ledoit&amp;amp;Wolf in their work: Improved estimation of the covariance matrix of stock returns with an application to portfolio selection, which can be found here.
If you also want to take a look on the original programming source, check the Michael’s Wolf website.
covMarket &amp;lt;- function(x, shrink = TRUE) {# some operations work better with the matrix classif (is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much shrinkage does the stock market requires?</title>
      <link>/2018/09/05/how-much-shrinkage-does-the-stock-market-requires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/05/how-much-shrinkage-does-the-stock-market-requires/</guid>
      <description>Shrinkage is hardly new in finance. In 1956, Charles Stein published a famous paper called Inadmissibility of the usual estimator for the mean of a multivariate normal distribution. In his work, he shows that, if the sum of the squares of the errors (SSE) is used as a loss function, then, for $ n \geq 2 $, the sample mean is not an optimal estimator. It can be improved by exploring the trade-off among bias and variance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many stocks in the S&amp;P 500 do follow a random-walk?</title>
      <link>/2018/08/27/how-many-stocks-in-the-s-p-500-do-follow-a-random-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/27/how-many-stocks-in-the-s-p-500-do-follow-a-random-walk/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning (ML) models are trendy and gaining popularity in finance. Practitioners noticed that little help can come from asymptotic theory if the researcher is constrained by the number of observations (in which \(n \rightarrow \infty\) do never happens).
The solution offered by a great deal of ML models is a complete twist in econometric tradition. Forget about odd features and ugly names, like autocorrelation, multicollinearity and heteroskedasticity. Just pay attention to the forecasts: are they good or not?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>