<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How much shrinkage does the stock market requires?</title>
      <link>/2018/09/05/how-much-shrinkage-does-the-stock-market-requires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/05/how-much-shrinkage-does-the-stock-market-requires/</guid>
      <description>Shrinkage is hardly new in finance. In 1956, Charles Stein published a famous paper called Inadmissibility of the usual estimator for the mean of a multivariate normal distribution. In this work, he shows that, if the sum of the squares of the errors (SSE) is used as a loss function, then, for $ n \geq 2 $, the sample mean is not an optimal estimator and can be improved by exploring the trade-off among bias and variance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many stocks in the S&amp;P 500 do follow a random-walk?</title>
      <link>/2018/08/27/how-many-stocks-in-the-s-p-500-do-follow-a-random-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/27/how-many-stocks-in-the-s-p-500-do-follow-a-random-walk/</guid>
      <description>There has been a huge growth of machine learning models’ in finance. The underlying idea behind those models is that a if the data is identically and independent distributed (i.i.d.) the statistician can use the law of large numbers (LLN) and the Glivenko-Canteli theorem to uncover the asymptotic behavior of the “true” distribution, which is, in fact, unknown. As the number of observations increase, closer and closer we get to the true values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Brazilian Debt</title>
      <link>/2018/08/06/brazilian-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/06/brazilian-debt/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will show how you can recursively download macroeconomic data covered by the IMF using the Quandl package. To motivate the application, the Brazilian public debt will be used as a variable of interest.
If you are familiar with Quandl you probably heard about the Quandl.search() function. What it does is try to look for a database that matches a specific pattern that you may have interest in, like “oil”, or “GDP”, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>