<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shrinkage on Bernardo Reckziegel</title>
    <link>/tags/shrinkage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shrinkage on Bernardo Reckziegel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/shrinkage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation Error Visualized</title>
      <link>/2019/02/27/estimation-error-visualized/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/27/estimation-error-visualized/</guid>
      <description>The objective of economic models is to dress common-sense into mathematical formalism1. For some economic models, however, real data is too scare to achieve good statistical analysis. This scarcity of data leads to estimation-error2 (the econometricians enemy number one).
By estimation-error I mean: the researcher is never certain about the true data generating process (DGP) of the phenomenon at hand. As Allan Timmermann and Graham Elliott argue, economic models can be thought as a condense representation of reality, in which mispecifification flourish naturally3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Covariance Matrix</title>
      <link>/2018/09/08/a-covariance-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/08/a-covariance-matrix/</guid>
      <description>The function bellow is a transcription from the MATLAB code done by Ledoit&amp;amp;Wolf in their work: Improved estimation of the covariance matrix of stock returns with an application to portfolio selection, which can be found here.
If you also want to take a look on the original programming source, check the Michael’s Wolf website.
covMarket &amp;lt;- function(x, shrink = TRUE) {# some operations work better with the matrix classif (is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much shrinkage does the stock market requires?</title>
      <link>/2018/09/05/how-much-shrinkage-does-the-stock-market-requires/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/05/how-much-shrinkage-does-the-stock-market-requires/</guid>
      <description>Shrinkage is hardly new in finance. In 1956, Charles Stein published a famous paper called Inadmissibility of the usual estimator for the mean of a multivariate normal distribution. In his work, he shows that, if the sum of the squares of the errors (SSE) is used as a loss function, then, for $ n \geq 2 $, the sample mean is not an optimal estimator. It can be improved by exploring the trade-off among bias and variance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>